(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T13:44:02.448652",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
強くなれる
I learned the reason
なれる理由を知った
to become strong,
僕を連れて進め
take me and go forward!
泥だらけの走馬灯に酔う
Intoxicated by the muddy lantern light,
凍る心 震える手は
my frozen heart and trembling hands
掴みたいものがある
have something they want to grasp.
それだけさ
That's all.
夜の匂いに
In the scent of the night—
(I'll spend all thirty nights)
(I'll spend all thirty nights)—
空睨んで
staring into the sky,
(Staring into the sky)
変わっていけるのは自分自身だけ
the only thing I can change is myself.
それだけさ
That's all.
強く慣れる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I've learned the reason I could become strong; take me with you and push forward!
どうしたって! 消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what! The dreams I can't erase, the present I can't stop—
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can become strong for someone's sake,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
then thank you, oh sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
Defeated by the world, I learned the meaning of defeat.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ！ 運命を照らして
Bloom proudly, flower of crimson lotus! Illuminate my destiny.
稲光りの雑音が耳を刺す 戸惑う心
The noise of lightning pierces my ears, my heart hesitates.
優しいだけじゃ守れないものがある 分かってるけど
There are things that cannot be protected by mere kindness; I know that, but...
水面下で絡まる善悪 透けて見える偽善に天罰
Good and evil intertwine beneath the surface, divine punishment on transparent hypocrisy.
I don't need you
異端の花より 挑み続けて咲いた一輪が美しい
More than a natural prodigy, a single flower that kept challenging and blooming is beautiful.
乱暴に敷き詰められた トゲだらけの道も
Even the road roughly paved and filled with thorns
本気の僕だけに現れるから 乗り越えてみせるよ
will reveal itself only to my earnest self, so I'll overcome it.
簡単にかたづけられた 守れなかった夢も
The dreams easily dismissed and left unprotected
紅蓮的心臓に根を生やして この血に宿っている
take root in the crimson heart and dwell within this blood.
人知れず 儚い散りゆく結末 無情に破れた 悲鳴の風吹く
Unnoticed, a fleeting end scattering away, the ruthless, torn wind of screams blows.
誰かの笑う影 誰かの泣き声 誰もが幸せを願っている
Someone's smiling shadow, someone's crying voice, everyone is wishing for happiness.
どうしたって! 消せない夢も 止まれない今も 誰かのために強くなれるなら
No matter what! The dreams I can't erase, the present I can't stop—if I can become strong for someone's sake,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
then thank you, oh sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
Defeated by the world, I learned the meaning of defeat.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ！ 運命を照らして
Bloom proudly, flower of crimson lotus! Illuminate my destiny.
運命を照らして
Illuminate my destiny.
Oh no! Everything is burnt down!
My house and the entire village is destroyed!
What is going on?
Are you all right?
A giant monster burned down my entire village with its fire breath!
That is bad.
Do you know where that monster is heading?
I think it's headed to the next village.
Don't worry, I shall take care of it for you so it won't destroy the other village too.
Don't worry, I'll take care of it so it won't destroy the other village too!
In order to do that, I need to collect power by singing and music.
So please, lend me your power, oh dear villager!
Oh, I will.
星を廻せ 世界のまんなかで
Spin the stars, right in the center of the world
くしゃみすれば どこかの森で蝶が乱舞
If I sneeze, butterflies flutter in a forest somewhere
君が守るドアのかぎ デタラメ
The key to the door you protect is nonsense
恥ずかしい物語 舐め合っても ライオンは強い
Even if we share an embarrassing story, the lion is strong
生き残りたい 生き残りたい
I want to survive, I want to survive
まだ生きていたくなる
I feel like I still want to live
星座の導きでいま、見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other just now
生き残りたい 途方にくれて キラリ枯れてゆく
I want to survive, lost at what to do, withering away in a sparkle
本気の身体 見せつけるまで 私は眠らない
Until I show off my serious self, I won't sleep
風はやがて 東へ向かうだろう
The wind will head toward the east before long
高気圧 この星の氷河を襲う
High pressure attacks the glaciers of this planet
誘い水を飲んだ 胸が辛い
My chest aches after drinking the priming water
遠巻きな物語り かじり合う 骨の奥まで
A distant story gnaws at us, deep down to the bone
生き残りたい 生き残りたい まだ生きていたくなる
I want to survive, I want to survive, I feel like I still want to live
星座の導きでいま、見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other just now
生き残りたい 途方にくれて キラリ枯れてゆく
I want to survive, lost at what to do, withering away in a sparkle
本気の身体 見せつけるまで 私は眠らない
Until I show off my serious self, I won't sleep
何しに生まれたの?
What was I born for?
何しにここにいる?
What am I here for?
生き残りたい 埋まらない傷 光恐れてた
I want to survive, unburied wounds feared the light
許された命が 今惹かれ合った
Our lives, permitted, attracted each other just now
彷徨い果てて 君のとなりで 火照り鎮めたい
My wandering is over, I want to quell my blushing beside you
本気の身体 見せつけるまで 私は眠らない
Until I show off my serious self, I won't sleep
生き残りたい
I want to survive
崖っぷちでいい
I'm fine on the edge of a cliff
君を愛してる 芽生えた命が 今光りあった
I love you. Awoken lives shone together just now
狂気に変えて 祈り捧ぐよ 君を愛してる
Turning it into madness, I offer a prayer, I love you
星座の導きで...
By the guidance of the constellations...
生き残りたい まだ生きていたい
I want to survive, I still want to live
君を愛してる
I love you
本気のこころ 見せつけるまで 私は眠らない
Until I show off my serious heart, I won't sleep
羽根もない この私が
With no wings at all,
憧れてた あの空
the sky I longed for...
背伸びして 星を掴む
Reaching up to catch the stars,
真似をしてみた
I tried imitating them.
負けないで 願いさえも 飲み込む闇
Never giving in, even to the darkness that swallows our wishes,
それでも 手探りで
still, fumbling in the dark,
夢の欠片 集めにいくよ
I'm going to gather the fragments of my dreams.
ただグルグル回る 写真の中
Spinning around and around inside the photograph,
走っても走っても 辿り着けなくて
even if I run and run, I can't reach it.
先を行く君の背中 ばかりを見ていた
I was only looking at your back as you went ahead.
いつか超えられる もうと強くなりたい
Someday I want to surpass you and become stronger!
たったひとり 生まれてきた
Born all alone,
その記憶も なくして
even losing those memories,
泣き声も 届かないと
even if my cries won't reach anyone,
嘆いてみても 信じていい？
even if I lament, can I still believe?
大きな木に しがみついた
Clinging to a giant tree,
爪痕 あの空へ
leaving claw marks toward that sky,
近づこうとしている 私が
I, who am trying to get closer—
風が雲を 流して
as the wind blows the clouds away...
星が降る
Stars are falling...
羽根もない この私が
With no wings at all,
憧れてた あの空
the sky I longed for...
背伸びして 星を掴む
reaching up high to catch the stars,
真似をしてみた
I tried imitating them.
負けないで 願いさえも 飲み込む闇
Never giving in, even to the darkness that swallows our wishes,
それでも 手探りで
still, fumbling in the dark,
夢の欠片 集めにいくよ
I'm going to gather the fragments of my dreams.
I think, after all this singing, my power is still not enough to defeat the giant pink monster! Ahahaha!
I heard you, young warrior. I can help you with your worry.
As I, the keeper of the legendary weapon Nut Blade, will lend you its power.
Is this the voice of the Fire Blade priestess?
Yes, you are right. I will lend you the power of this Nut Blade if you can prove yourself that you have the spirit to fight the pink giant monster.
Huh? Okay!
(why?) 胸に刻め 時代のリーダー
(Why?) Engrave in your heart the leader of the era.
(who?) 見た目よりはかなりクレーバー
(Who?) Much cleverer than you'd think.
(fool!) 乾いた心 すさむよりは
(Fool!) Rather than letting a dry heart wither,
(fight!) 時に泣いてみれば
(Fight!) Try crying sometimes;
見えてくる明日に駆けるのは
running toward the visible tomorrow
紛れもなく新しい自分
is undoubtedly a brand new you.
誰かのためでなく
Not for anyone else's sake,
ただもっと上を目指す
just aiming ever higher.
dragon screamer!
(why i do? why i do? hoo!)
昇る龍のようだ
Like a rising dragon,
(why i do? why i do? hoo!)
金の光が呼んだ未来が
the future summoned by golden light
導くんだ僕らを
will guide us forward.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
(why?) 見えているのに はるかなゴールは
(Why?) Even though it's in sight, the distant goal is
(where?) 見た目よりはかなり harder
(Where?) considerably harder than it looks.
(hard!) 君が踏み出す勇気持てば
(Hard!) If you have the courage to take a step,
(fight!) やがて開く道が
(Fight!) the path will soon open up.
目指すべき場所選ぶのは
Choosing the place you should aim for
まぎれもなく新しい自分
is undoubtedly a brand new you.
翼を手にした君は
You, who have obtained wings,
どんな山をも越える
can cross any mountain.
dragon screamer! (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
叫ぶ龍のような
Like a roaring dragon,
(why i say? why i say? hoo!)
銀の嵐が吹き飛ばすんだ
a silver storm blows away
迷いとか恐れを
all hesitation and fear.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
oh my way 走り出せ!
Oh my way, start running!
駆け抜けてくライバルという風
Run right through the wind called rivals.
in that case 気持ち high pace で征す
In that case, conquer at a high pace.
光りさす明日 まだ見ぬ上目指す
Aim for the unseen heights in tomorrow's light.
諦めず探し続ける finally
Never giving up, searching forever finally
いつまでも変わらぬ夢 victory
An unchanging dream forever, victory.
空に浮かぶ dragon 背中に光りさす明日
A dragon floating in the sky, tomorrow light on its back
世界をその手に
Take the world in your hands.
dragon screamer! (why i do? why i do? hoo!)
昇る龍のようだ (why i do? why i do? hoo!)
Like a rising dragon! (Why I do? Why I do? Hoo!)
金の光が呼んだ未来が導くんだ僕らを
The future summoned by golden light will guide us.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
dragon screamer! (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
叫ぶ龍のような (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
Like a roaring dragon! (Why I say? Why I say? Hoo!)
銀の嵐が吹き飛ばすんだ迷いとか恐れを
A silver storm blows away hesitation and fear.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
oh my way 走り出せ!
Oh my way, start running!
駆け抜けてくライバルという風
Run right through the wind called rivals.
in that case 気持ち high pace で征す
In that case, conquer at a high pace.
光りさす明日 まだ見ぬ上目指す
Aim for the unseen heights in tomorrow's light.
諦めず探し続ける finally
Never giving up, searching forever finally
いつまでも変わらぬ夢 victory
An unchanging dream forever, victory.
dragon screamer! (why i do? why i do? hoo!)
昇る龍のようだ (why i do? why i do? hoo!)
Like a rising dragon! (Why I do? Why I do? Hoo!)
金の光が呼んだ未来が導くんだ僕らを
The future summoned by golden light will guide us.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
dragon screamer! (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
叫ぶ龍のような (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
Like a roaring dragon! (Why I say? Why I say? Hoo!)
銀の嵐が吹き飛ばすんだ迷いとか恐れを
A silver storm blows away hesitation and fear.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
dragon screamer! (why i do? why i do? hoo!)
昇る龍のようだ (why i do? why i do? hoo!)
Like a rising dragon! (Why I do? Why I do? Hoo!)
金の光が呼んだ未来が導くんだ僕らを
The future summoned by golden light will guide us.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
dragon screamer! (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
叫ぶ龍のような (why i say? why i say? hoo!)
Like a roaring dragon! (Why I say? Why I say? Hoo!)
銀の嵐が吹き飛ばすんだ迷いとか恐れを
A silver storm blows away hesitation and fear.
dragon screamer! dragon fever! no question!
You have proven me your spirit. I shall bestow upon you the Nut Blade.
Thank you. I shall use this weapon to defeat the monster.
Now I have the Nut Blade, I shall continue my journey to defeat the giant pink monster.
If my hunch was right, I think...
I should go through the forest next.
Oh no! What happened to you, oh mighty dragon?
ピンクの巨獣にやられた。
I was attacked by a pink beast.
今は力が入らん。
I have no strength left right now.
すぐ破壊されてしまった。
It was destroyed in an instant.
Oh no, that is bad.
I can help you recover if you can take me straight to the giant monster in exchange.
任せておけ。
Leave it to me.
偶然から始まる 必然の一場面
A chance beginning, an inevitable scene.
遠くに見えたのは 揺れる赤色
Seen far away was swaying crimson.
不思議な森の奥で 見つけた黒い影と 何か始まる予感、怖くて逃げ出した
In the depths of a mysterious forest, I found a black shadow.
「出会い」は終わりに続くシナリオ だから、わざわざ遠回りをした
An encounter is a scenario leading to an end.
会いたい、なんて 触りたい、なんて 話したい、なんて思わないかよ
Wanting to meet, touch, and talk... I don't think like that.
わい君と狡い僕が「出会う」 其れが終わりさ 残酷だって罵ってだって運命は変わらない
You, so cute, and me, so cunning, meet. That's the end.
ああどうして、君が？ どうして、僕が？ おおかみと赤ずきん、なんだ
Ah, why you? Why me? We're a wolf and Red Riding Hood.
きっと君は今日もこの道を訪れる
Surely you'll visit this path again today.
そして僕は今日もずっと見守るしかできない
And I can only keep watching over you today as well.
君はあの木の陰で いつも通り、隠れている 私は気付か振りのしたまま通り過ぎた
You're hiding behind that tree as usual, and I passed by.
視線は絡まない 声は届かない ため息だけが虚しく重なる
Our gazes don't meet, our voices don't reach, only sighs pile up.
会えなくって 触れなくって 話せなくっていいから 頼りない君と不器用な僕が 其処に居るだけでいいんだ
Not being able to meet, touch, or talk is fine, just us being here.
これが恋だって言わないなら 言葉なんて、無くていい
If this isn't love, we don't even need words.
ああ考えたって考えたってエンディングは変わらない
Thinking and thinking, the ending won't change.
会いたかったんだ 触りたかったんだ 話したかった、ほんとは かわいい君と優しい僕が 出会い、結ばれる結末 何回だって何回だって神様に願ったよ
I wanted to meet, touch, and talk—truly, I prayed to God.
でも…悲しいくらい、悲しいくらい おおかみと赤ずきん、なんだ
But painfully, painfully, we're a wolf and Red Riding Hood.
泣いている君を慰めたくて 伸ばした腕が、震える 愛しているよ 抱きしめたいよ だけど、できないんだよ…！
Wanting to comfort you crying, my extended arm trembles.
どう足掻いたって どう願ったって 爪も牙も消えない だから、ただ待っているよ 君の涙が止まるまで、あの木の陰でずっと…
No matter how I wish, claws and fangs remain, so I'll just wait.
視線は絡まない 声は届かない ため息だけが虚しく重なる
Our gazes don't meet, our voices don't reach, only sighs pile up.
会えなくって 触れなくって 話せなくっていいから 頼りない君と不器用な僕が 其処に居るだけでいいんだ これが恋だって言わないなら 言葉なんて、無くていい
Not being able to meet, touch, or talk is fine, we don't need words.
ああ考えたって考えたってエンディングは変わらない
Thinking and thinking, the ending won't change.
会いたかったんだ 触りたかったんだ 話したかったほんとは かわいい君と優しい僕が出会い結ばれるエンド
I wanted to meet, touch, and talk—truly, the end of us meeting.
何回だって何回だって神様に願ったよ
How many times I prayed to God.
でも悲しいくらい悲しいくらい おおかみと赤ずきんなんだ
But painfully, painfully, we're a wolf and Red Riding Hood.
泣いてる君を慰めたくて伸ばした腕が震える 愛しているよ抱きしめたいよだけどできないんだよ
Wanting to comfort you crying, my extended arm trembles.
だから、ただ待ってるよ 君の涙が止まるまで、あの木の先で ずっと…
That's why I'll just wait until your tears stop, beyond that tree...
会いたかったんだ 触れかかったんだ 話したかった 本当は可愛い君と優しい僕が出会い結ばれるエンド
I wanted to meet, touch, and talk—truly, the end of us meeting.
何回だって何回だって神様に願ったよ
How many times I prayed to God.
でも悲しいくらい悲しいくらいおおかみと赤ずきんなんだ
But painfully, painfully, we're a wolf and Red Riding Hood.
泣いてる君をなぐさめたくて伸ばしたうでが震える 愛しているよ抱きしめたいよだけどできないんだよ
Wanting to comfort you crying, my extended arm trembles.
だからただ待ってるよ君の涙がやむまであの木の先で ずっと…
That's why I'll just wait until your tears stop, beyond that tree...
Ah, here you go! If you eat this, you can recover super quick!
感謝す。
I am grateful.
よし、完全回復だ。
All right, fully recovered.
今すぐ怪獣の元へ案内しよう。
I'll guide you to the monster right now.
Okay, let's go!
飛べFLY HIGH!! 汗と血と涙で輝く翼で
Fly, FLY HIGH!! With wings shining with sweat, blood, and tears...
if i love you, would you love me too
utara ku kecil dahulu
North of my little past
the love will last it will
selamanya ku kan peduli, right?
Forever I'll care, right?
to me
broken thing have i become
and you see, life is pain
truly i had enough
ordinary day it seems
the clouds of love in the sky
painted colors in my paradise
titik hujan menyegarkan segala
Raindrops refresh everything
bunga-bunga emosi manusia
Flowers of human emotion
mekar dan berkembang megah selamanya
Blooming and developing magnificently forever
will i love you like you love me too
utara mu lebih dahulu
North of yours earlier
the love will last it will
selamanya ku kan ada di sini
Forever I'll be here
to me
enchanting have i become
and you see life is fair
truly i am enough
ordinary day it seems
the cloud of lies in the sky
painted color in my paradise
titik hujan menghapuskan segala
Raindrops wash away everything
luka, duka emosi manusia
Wounds, grief of human emotion
rapuh dan terjatuh, lelah di dunia
Fragile and fallen, tired in the world
the halo
lingers on my ego
blinding light that radiates
evaporates the sad in me
a soundless whisper
follow me, never let go
bahagia jadi nyata
Happiness becomes real
berdua
Together
to me
obsessive have i become
and you see life is fair
never i had enough
ordinary i will be
the cloud and the color of rainbow
start to show in my paradise
titik hujan meleburkan segala
Raindrops melt everything
luka, duka emosi manusia
Wounds, grief of human emotion
rapuh dan terlalu lelah di dunia
Fragile and too tired in the world
hi, finally i can see you
awan gelap yang membentuk aku
Dark clouds that form me
titik hujan membasuh
Raindrops wash clean
bunga-bunga perasaan
Flowers of feelings
dan melebur satu warna yang bermakna
And melt into one meaningful color
if i love you, would you love me too
utara ku kecil dahulu
North of my little past
the love will last it will
selamanya ku kan peduli, right?
Forever I'll care, right?
to me
broken thing have i become
and you see, life is pain
truly i had enough
ordinary day it seems
the clouds of love in the sky
painted colors in my paradise
titik hujan menyegarkan segala
Raindrops refresh everything
bunga-bunga emosi manusia
Flowers of human emotion
mekar dan berkembang megah selamanya
Blooming and developing magnificently forever
will i love you like you love me too
utara mu lebih dahulu
North of yours earlier
the love will last it will
selamanya ku kan ada di sini
Forever I'll be here
to me
enchanting have i become
and you see life is fair
truly i am enough
ordinary day it seems
the cloud of lies in the sky
painted color in my paradise
titik hujan menghapuskan segala
Raindrops wash away everything
luka, duka emosi manusia
Wounds, grief of human emotion
rapuh dan terjatuh, lelah di dunia
Fragile and fallen, tired in the world
the halo
lingers on my ego
blinding light that radiates
evaporates the sad in me
a soundless whisper
follow me, never let go
bahagia jadi nyata
Happiness becomes real
berdua
Together
to me
obsessive have i become
and you see life is fair
never i had enough
ordinary i will be
the cloud and the color of rainbow
start to show in my paradise
titik hujan meleburkan segala
Raindrops melt everything
if i love you, would you love me too
If I love you, would you love me too
utara ku kecil dahulu
If you loved me first long ago,
The love will last, it will
selamanya ku kan peduli
I will care for you forever,
right?
To me
broken thing have I become
a broken thing have I become,
and you see, life is pain
truly I had enough
truly I've had enough.
ordinary day it seems
An ordinary day it seems,
the clouds of love in the sky
painted colors in my paradise
titik hujan menyegarkan segala
Raindrops refreshing everything,
bunga-bunga emosi manusia
flowers of human emotions,
mekar dan berkembang megah selamanya
blooming and growing magnificently forever.
will i love you like you love me too
utara mu lebih dahulu
If you loved me first long ago,
the love will last, it will
selamanya ku kan ada di sini
I will always be right here.
to me
enchanting have I become
an enchanting thing have I become,
and you see, life is fair
truly I am enough
ordinary day it seems
An ordinary day it seems,
the cloud of lies in the sky
painted color in my paradise
titik hujan menghapuskan segala
Raindrops wiping away everything,
luka, duka emosi manusia
wounds and sorrows of human emotions,
rapuh dan terjatuh, lelah di dunia
fragile and fallen, weary in this world.
the halo lingers on my ego
blinding light that radiates
evaporates the sad in me
a soundless whisper
follow me, never let go
bahagia jadi nyata
Happiness becomes reality,
berdua
together.
to me
obsessive have I become
an obsessive thing have I become,
and you see, life is fair
never i had enough
and I never had enough.
ordinary i will be
the cloud and the color of rainbow
the cloud and the color of the rainbow
start to show in my paradise
titik hujan meleburkan segala
Raindrops melting away everything,
luka, duka emosi manusia
wounds and sorrows of human emotions,
rapuh dan terlalu lelah di dunia
fragile and exhausted in this world.
hi, finally i can see you
awan gelap yang membentuk aku
dark clouds that shaped who I am,
titik hujan membasuh bersih
raindrops washing it clean,
bunga-bunga perasaan
flowers of feelings,
dan melebur menjadi satu warna yang bermakna
and melting into one meaningful color.
ひらひら葉落月 ハオチズキ
Flitter-flutter, falling leaves, haochizuki,
夜明けが見たいって 叫んだ空
"I want to see the dawn," the sky screamed.
暗く暗く陰と影の死の夜も
Through dark, dark shades and shadows of death's night,
深く深く耐えて芽差す地の恵
enduring deep, deep, sprouting earth's bounty.
来たる光照らす新生の世に
In the coming light-illuminated newborn world,
高く高く舞え 日晴 ヒバリ
dance high, high, sunny sky, skylark.
神様気取りのマダム達が
Self-proclaimed god-like madams
世界をa.i.して壊しました
ruined the world with AI.
誰のもの誰のもの我のもの邪魔ものは廃した
"Mine, all mine, get rid of all obstacles!"
カントがなんとか言ってたって エゴに掴まれて拒まないんだ
Even if Kant said something, gripped by ego they don't refuse.
丸足りないもの足りない死にたくない 机械仕掛けの狂った声で
Not enough, lacking, don't want to die, with a clockwork crazy voice,
大人達が言う we doin' holy war for luv
adults say, "We doin' holy war for luv."
うんざりだよ 心動む愛してるわ
I'm sick of it, syndrome, "I love you."
もうやめてよ 心ってモノを量って切って 売りで幸せですか？
Stop it already, measuring hearts and selling them—is that happy?
造られたshowcase もう抜け出せない期待 未来 奇跡の鍵
A crafted showcase, can't escape: expectation, future, the key of miracle.
魂を一体どこに隠した？
Where on earth did you hide the soul?
神よ、科学よ、イブよ
O God, Science, Eve!
天アマつ少女オトメ 詩ウタと舞え ヒバリの天ソラ
Heavenly maiden, dance with poetry, skylark's sky.
輪廻 電生 機械論 進化の論
Samsara, rebirth, mechanism, theory of evolution,
人が人ではなく 堕ち無くなる 地に片嚙 カタバミ よ 嘆 コラ えろ
humans ceasing to be human, falling endlessly...
歌だけは未来へ届くよう 天 ソラ から空へと繋げるよう
May only song reach the future, connecting sky to sky...
限りなく鳴る光 ヒバリ達を残す
Leaving behind endlessly ringing light, the skylarks.
なんて絵本を聴かせてくれたっけ
What kind of picture book did you read to me?
ねえ リリアン
Hey, Lilian.
「2人のこと愛してる」
"I love the two of us."
嘘でもいいから一度だけでも聞かせてよ
Even if it's a lie, let me hear it just once!
輪廻転生 回路 進化論
Samsara, rebirth, circuit, theory of evolution,
人が人であれなく 死に固まりをこらえろと
humans ceasing to be human, enduring the clump of death.
叩けよ未来へ届くよ
Beat it, reaching toward the future!
空からそれへと繋げるよ
Connecting from the sky to that!
限りなく鳴く日 張り裂けたちを覗く
Crying endlessly, peering into the torn-apart days.
なんて本を聞かせてくれたっけ
What kind of book did you read to me?
メリディアの二人のこと
About the two of us in Meridia,
愛してる 嘘でもいいから
"I love you"—even if it's a lie,
一度だけでも聞かせてよ
let me hear it just once!
どこやってどこで笑ってました
Where on earth, where did we laugh?
今は幸せですか 置き去りのまま
Are you happy now, left behind?
届かない思い ごめん何でやれんかったかな
Feelings that don't reach—sorry, why couldn't I do it?
悲しい思い出は 風に隠した
Sad memories were hidden in the wind.
歌よ あなたの元へ
O song, to your side,
天アマつ少女オトメ 時を舞え ヒバリの天ソラ
heavenly maiden, dance through time, skylark's sky.
ひとりでも笑って生きるんだ
Living and smiling even all alone.
ひとりでは生きていけないんだ
But not being able to live all alone.
ずっと交わんだり 愛したり
Always intersecting, loving,
恨んで壊して それでも縋って生きるよ
resenting, destroying, yet clinging and living on!
心ってモノを量って切って 売りで幸せですか？
Measuring and cutting hearts and selling them—is that happy?
造られたshowcase もう抜け出せない期待 未来 奇跡の鍵
A crafted showcase, can't escape: expectation, future, the key of miracle.
魂を一体どこに隠した？
Where on earth did you hide the soul?
神よ、科学よ、イブよ
O God, Science, Eve!
天アマつ少女オトメ 詩ウタと舞え ヒバリの天ソラ
Heavenly maiden, dance with poetry, skylark's sky.
夜明けを告げたらいこう 姫 雛鳥 ヒバリ の天ソラ
Once dawn is announced, let's go—princess, fledglings, skylark's sky.
Hi everyone!
Woo!
Now, now, now!
How was my performance?
Do you like it?
Do you guys have fun?
And also for celebrating my victory and my birthday,
we have special merch! Yes!
So here's the merch!
Woohoo!
Whoa!
How cool is it? And it's not only cool.
This year's merch was designed to be useful, too!
So let's have a closer look, shall we? First up,
Ooh! Wow!
It's an awesome A3 tapestry drawn by nateral-sensei!
Whoa!
The whole illustration just—woah, it looks super awesome!
It looks so cool!
You can see that I'm holding my beloved...
Just look at that! Warrior Risu with full dark side!
Isn't that awesome?
Woo! Don't miss it!
And also don't forget you guys got to buy at least five, okay?
And I think let's see what we have next!
Woo!
A super cute tumbler for everybody, so you guys won't forget to hydrate.
Um, you can use it to drink water, and you can use it pretty much always, so be sure to use it every day, okay?
And next, we have this!
Woah, a smartphone ring!
Ooh, so you can be um, super comfortable and remember me when you're um, holding your phone.
And it also will secure your phone in your hand, a very, very convenient.
And I think let's see the full set now!
Woo! Woah, there's so much stuffs actually!
And also, don't forget we have the full set purchase bonus here!
So I will explain it a little bit, um, for those of you who purchase the full set will also receive a signed foil-stamped postcard!
And for my super RisuNars who purchase the limited edition full set will receive a postcard autographed by none other than me, autographed by me!
Isn't that awesome? Woah!
And the pre-order window is only a month, so make sure that you don't miss it!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, also one more thing!
Did you guys listen to my new original song, "Hoshi ga Furu"?
It will be officially released after this stream at midnight JST, JST, okay? On my YouTube channel.
So go listen to it, and um, maybe who knows that later we will have MV for it? I don't know!
And last, but not least, for all of you who joined my membership, you don't want to miss a special additional 3D performance in membership just right after this show has ended.
If you haven't joined my membership yet, do not hesitate because the extra show is going to be mind-boggling!
What are you waiting for? Join membership now! Woo!
Woo!
Oops, um, but I think the time is up, aw, and I have to continue.
But yes, I have to continue with the membership show now.
So thank you so much everyone for your support for this whole six years especially,
and thank you for celebrating my birthday together with me!
So bye-bye RisuNars!